Guide to the Meyer Schapiro Collection,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VIII: Works of art, 1920s-1980s
  - Subseries VIII.2: Prints and Drawings, 1920s-1980s
    - 1001-1121 After RVR [Rembrandt van Rijn] - Syndics (Box 11)
    - 1002-1121 Descending Order of Power (Box 11)
      Two sheets. 4 x 6 Ink on paper
    - 1003-1121 "En Lisant" [After ?] #1 (Box 11)
      9 1/2 x 6 3/8 Conte crayon on paper
    - 1004-1121 Rawsonville (Box 11)
    - 1005-1121 ["Matyr"] #2 (Box 11)
      9 1/2 x 6 1/4 Conte crayon on paper
    - 1006-1121 ["Matyr"] #3 (Box 11)
    - 1007-1121 Country Road (Box 11)
      5 1/2 x 8 3/8 Conte crayon on paper
    - 1008-1121 Emerging Infant Head - Profile #6 (Box 11)
      4 7/8 x 7 5/8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1009-1121 Emerging Head #5 (Box 11)
    - 1010-1121 Face in Shading #7 (Box 11)
    - 1011-1121 Egyptian Fantasy #4 (Box 11)
    - 1012-1121 Fantasy #3 (Box 11)
    - 1013-1121 Emerging Head #7 - [Insect on Comb] #8 (Box 11)
    - 1014-1121 [Beach Scene] (Box 11)
    - 1015-1121 Female (Box 11)
    - 1016-1121 Country House (Box 11)
      3 5/8 x 6 Ink on paper
    - 1017-1121 Miriam (Box 11)
    - 1018-1121 Miriam and Doll (Box 11)
      11 x 8 13/8 Pastels on paper
    - 1019-1121 Sketch for Painting (Box 11)
    - 1020-1121 Sketch for Painting of Joe (Box 11)
    - 1021-1121 Sketch for Painting of Apple-Picking (Box 11)
    - 1022-1121 Sketch for Painting of Apple-Picking (Box 11)
    - 1023-1121 Meeting (Box 11)
    - 1024-1121 Lillian Reading (Box 11)
    - 1025-1121 Meeting (Box 11)
    - 1026-1121 Meeting (Box 11)
    - 1027-1121 Meeting (Box 11)
    - 1028-1121 Meeting (Box 11)
    - 1029-1121 Vermont (Box 11)
    - 1030-1121 Color scopecontents (Box 11)
    - 1031-1121 Sculpture by Jacques Lipchitz From Memory (Box 11)
    - 1032-1121 Study of Lines and Triangles (Box 11)
    - 1033-1121 Study of Lines and Triangles (Box 11)
    - 1034-1121 Eye-Parasols (Box 11)
    - 1035-1121 Miriam Eating (Box 11)
      3 x 5 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1036-1121 Miriam in Vermont (Box 11)
      6 3/4 x 9 Oil paint on paper
    - 1037-1121 Miriam in Vermont (Box 11)
      6 37/8 x 9 Oil paint on paper
    - 1038-1121 Study (Box 11)
      6 1/4 x 9 Oil paint on paper
    - 1039-1121 Car in Repair (Box 11)
      Drawing on verso. 6 3/8 x 9 5/8 Crayon on paper
    - 1040-1121 Entwined Animals (Box 11)
      9 x 11 1/4 Crayon on paper
    - 1041-1121 Entwined Animals (Box 11)
    - 1042-1121 Vermont (Box 11)
      9 x 10 3/4 Gouache on paper
    - 1043-1121 Shapes Piled On Table (Box 12)
      9 1/2 x 12 3/4 Oil paint on paper
    - Miniatures (Box 12)
      12 x 9 Pastels on paper
    - 1045-1121 Abstraction - Diagonal Curvilinear Shapes #5 (Box 12)
    - 1046-1121 Following My Father's Elevated Train (Box 12)
      Inscribed on verso: Williamsburg. 12 x 8 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 1047-1121 Family in Vermont (Box 12)
    - 1048-1121 Winged Shapes - Abstraction (Box 12)
    - 1049-1121 Sailing with the Beasts - A Sketch (Box 12)
      9 1/2 x 13 1/4 Oil paint on paper
    - 1050-1121 Man Wrestling Bird (Box 12)
    - 1051-1121 Family in Vermont (Box 12)
    - 1052-1121 Winged Shapes - Abstraction (Box 12)
    - 1053-1121 Lillian (Box 12)
      5 x 8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - Miriam on Phone, 1054-1121 (Box 12)
      Two sheets. 3 1/2 x 5 1/2 Ink on paper
    - Family Picnic in Winhall River - Sketch for Painting, 1055-1121 (Box 12)
    - 1056-1121 Lillian (Box 12)
    - 1057-1121 Winhall Brook - Vermont (Box 12)
      4 x 5 7/8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1058-1121 Miriam (Box 12)
      8 1/2 x 12 Pastels on paper
    - 1059-1121 Vermont (Box 12)
      8 1/2 x 6 Pastels on paper
    - 1060-1121 Vermont House From East (Box 12)
      7 x 10 5/8 Watercolor on paper
    - 1061-1121 Vermont From Hill Looking West (Box 12)
      8 1/8 x 11 Oil paint on paper
    - 1062-1121 Vermont Shed (Box 12)
      7 3/4 x 11 Oil paint on paper
    - 1063-1121 End of the Shed - Vermont (Box 12)
      9 3/4 x 13 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1064-1121 Vermont House From Hill (Box 12)
    - 1065-1121 [Lillian] (Box 12)
      12 x 8 1/2 Crayon on paper
    - 1066-1121 Head of Woman (Box 12)
    - 1067-1121 Vermont Shed (Box 12)
      4 x 5 7/8 Ink on paper
    - 1068-1121 Vermont Landscape II (Box 12)
      6 1/8 x 9 1/2 Ink on paper
    - 1069-1121 From Cast of Chartres Head in Vermont (Box 12)
    - 1070-1121 Seated Woman (Box 12)
    - 1071-1121 Sailing with the Beasts (Box 12)
      Two sheets. 4 x 6 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1072-1121 Vermont House - Meyer, Lillian and the Children (Box 12)
      9 1/8 x 6 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1073-1121 Lillian (Box 12)
      11 x 7 1/2 Ink on paper
    - 1074-1121 Corner of Study - West 4th Street (Box 12)
      Drawn on verso of scrap of final examination for Fine Arts 175 - Modern Painting. 8 1/2 x 7 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1075-1121 Junk-Shop (Box 12)
    - 1076-1121 Darks in My Painting of Vermont House (Box 12)
      3 x 4 Ink and graphite pencil on paper
    - 1077-1121 Fanciful Map (Box 12)
      4 x 6 Ink and graphite pencil on paper
    - 1078-1121 House and Barn - Vermont (Box 12)
    - 1079-1121 Cubist Buildings (Box 12)
    - 1080-1121 Lillian Reading (Box 12)
    - 1081-1121 House Helper and Ernest - [Vermont] (Box 12)
      4 1/2 x 6 1/4 Ink on paper
    - 1082-1121 Woman Sleeping (Box 12)
      8 7/8 x 6 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1083-1121 Ballet (Box 12)
    - 1084-1121 Central Park (Box 12)
      5 3/4 x 7 5/8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1085-1121 Miriam (Box 12)
    - 1086-1121 Fantasy Landscape (Box 12)
    - 1087-1121 Abstract With Light (Box 12)
      9 x 11 1/2 Conte crayon on paper
    - 1088-1121 Vermont Landscape I (Box 12)
    - 1089-1121 Lillian Sketches (Box 12)
      12 x 8 1/2 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1090-1121 [Lillian] (Box 12)
    - 1091-1121 Ernest at 5 (Box 12)
    - 1092-1121 Head of Young Girl (Box 12)
    - 1093-1121 Lillian Wet Hair in Towel (Box 12)
    - 1094-1121 Sky Battle Over Church (Box 12)
      5 3/4 x 3 7/8 Ink on paper
    - 1095-1121 Pails and Kettles (Box 12)
    - 1096-1121 Lillian Sketches (Box 12)
    - 1097-1121 Head - Study (Box 12)
      13 1/4 x 9 1/2 Crayon on paper
    - 1098-1121 House and Barn - Vermont (Box 12)
    - >1099-1121 House and Barn with Wash-Line - Vermont (Box 12)
      9 1/2 x 13 Oil paint on paper
    - 1100-1121 Lillian (Box 12)
      9 x 7 3/4 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1101-1121 Chair and Pitcher - Abstraction (Box 12)
    - 1102-1121 Chair and Pitcher - Abstraction (Box 12)
    - 1103-1121 [Cat Playing Cat's Cradle] (Box 12)
    - 1104-1121 Rawsonville (Box 12)
      3 1/8 x 4 1/4 Crayon on paper
    - 1105-1121 Ernest - Colored By Ernest (Box 12)
      6 x 4 Pastels on paper
    - 1106-1121 Young Woman (Box 12)
    - 1107-1121 Woman Profile Body (Box 12)
      5 x 3 Ink on paper
    - 1108-1121 Artichoke (Box 12)
    - 1109-1121 Woman's Head (Box 12)
    - 1110-1121 Young Woman (Box 12)
    - 1111-1121 Young Woman (Box 12)
    - 1112-1121 Man with Mustache and Tie (Box 12)
    - 1113-1121 Landscape with Figures Carrying Body or Corpse (Box 12)
    - 1114-1121 Triptyche on a Table (Box 12)
    - 1115-1121 Ink Blots (Box 12)
    - 1116-1121 Looking Into Hall from Living Room - 279 West 4th Street (Box 12)
    - 1117-1121 Morris (Box 12)
    - 1118-1121 Morris - Violin (Box 12)
    - 1119-1121 [Landscape] (Box 12)
    - 1120-1121 Lillian with Towel on Head (Box 12)
    - 1121-1121 Lillian with Towel on Head (Box 12)
    - 1122-1121 Lillian with Towel on Head (Box 12)
    - 1123-1121 Lillian with Towel on Head (Box 12)
    - 1124-1121 Lillian on Queen Elizabeth (Box 12)
      Drawn on verso of RMS "Queen Elizabeth" stationery. 5 3/8 x 6 7/8 Ink on paper
    - 1125-1121 Wildflowers for Ernest (Box 12)
    - 1126-1121 Wildflowers for Ernest (Box 12)
    - 1127-1121 Wildflowers for Ernest (Box 12)
    - 1128-1121 Wildflowers for Ernest (Box 12)
    - 1129-1121 Royal Institution (Box 12)
      Inscribed: folding paper on wet ink. 5 7/8 x 4 Ink on paper
    - 1130-1121 Lillian (Box 12)
      3 7/8 x 6 Grpahite pencil on paper
    - 1131-1121 Dancing (Box 12)
    - 1132-1121 [Horses and Figure from Sculpture] (Box 12)
    - 1133-1121 Face (Box 12)
    - 1134-1121 Child's Head - [Ernest] (Box 12)
    - 1135-1121 Chinese Bronzes (Box 12)
      5 7/8 x 3 7/8 Ink on paper
    - 1136-1121 Scattered Dots (Box 12)
      6 1/8 x 4 Ink on paper
    - 1137-1121 Female Head (Box 12)
      6 x 9 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1138-1121 Figure (Box 12)
      4 1/8 x 6 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1139-1121 Lillian (Box 12)
    - 1140-1121 Hill House - Vermont (Box 12)
      5 1/8 x 7 1/4 Crayon on lined paper
    - 1141-1121 Miriam on the Phone (Box 12)
    - 1142-1121 Lillian Sketches (Box 12)
    - 1143-1121 Lillian Sketches (Box 12)
    - 1144-1121 Lillian and Ernest (Box 12)
      9 3/4 x 12 3/4 Charcoal on paper
    - 1145-1121 Lillian (Box 12)
      12 1/4 x 9 3/8 Ink on paper
    - 1146-1121 After English Miniature Painting of 13th Century (Box 12)
      9 3/8 x 5 1/2 Ink on paper
    - 1147-1121 Vermont House from South (Box 12)
      7 1/2x 11 Oil paint on paper
    - 1148-1121 A Fragment - Legs (Box 12)
    - 1149-1121 Untitled (Box 12)
    - 1150-1121 Landscape (Box 12)
    - 1151-1121 Zoomorphic Form Over Overlapping Shapes (Box 12)
      9 x 12 Crayon and watercolor on paper
    - 1152-1121 Black and White Abstraction (Box 12)
      9 x 12 Charcoall on paper
    - 1153-1121 Landscape with Farm House (Box 12)
      6 x 9 1/2 Ink on paper
    - 1154-1121 View of Side Roads and Mountains (Box 12)
      Inscribed on verso: Meadow and Glebe Mountain, Rawsonville, Vermont. 15x 11 Pastels on paper
    - 1155-1121 Vermont Landscape (Box 12)
      15 1/8 x 11 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 1156-1121 The Corner of the House and Garden - Vermont (Box 12)
      15 x 11 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1157-1121 Farm Meadows (Box 12)
      15 x 11 Oil paint on paper
    - 1158-1121 A Couple - Half Figures (Box 12)
    - 1159-1121 Vermont Landscape (Box 12)
      15 1/8 x 11 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1160-1121 House and Barns From West - Vermont (Box 12)
    - 1161-1121 Eve (Box 12)
    - 1162-1121 [Eve] (Box 12)
    - 1163-1121 Ernest and Miriam - Sketch for Painting (Box 12)
    - 1164-1121 Vermont (Box 12)
    - 1165-1121 Studio and Hillside - Rawsonville (Box 12)
      14 x 10 3/4 Oil paint on cardboard
    - 1166-1121 Abstraction (Box 12)
      11 1/8 x 15 Gouache on paper
    - 1167-1121 Vermont Meadow and Landscape (Box 12)
      12 x 8 1/2 Pastels on paper
    - 1168-1121 Sailing with the Beasts - A Sketch (Box 12)
      9 3/8 x 13 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1169-1121 Miriam in Vermont - Convalescent (Box 12)
      14 x 10 Oil paint on canvas board
    - 1170-1121 Sailing with the Beasts - A Sketch (Box 12)
    - 1171-1121 Sailing with the Beasts - A Sketch (Box 12)
      9 1/2 x 13 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1172-1121 Miriam and Ernest - Vermont Shed (Box 12)
      8 x 10 7/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1173-1121 Vermont Shed with Clouds and People (Box 12)
    - 1174-1121 Miriam and Ernest - Vermont (Box 12)
      6 7/8 x 8 7/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1175-1121 Vermont - Study (Box 12)
      5 3/4 x 5 7/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1176-1121 Sailing with the Beasts - A Sketch (Box 12)
    - 1177-1121 [Ernest] (Box 12)
      12 x 9 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 1178-1121 Miriam Reading (Box 12)
      12 1/2 x 9 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1179-1121 Still Life (Box 12)
      9 1/2 x 6 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 1180-1121 Lillian (Box 12)
    - 1181-1121 Lillian (Box 12)
      14 1/2 x 11 1/8 Crayon on paper
    - 1182-1121 Head - Study (Box 12)
      12 1/4 x 9 Crayon on paper
    - 1183-1121 Rubbing of Cover of Book by Hugh Miller (Box 12)
    - 1184-1121 Somewhere - Vermont (Box 12)
    - 1185-1121 Shed Door, Miriam and Ernest - Vermont (Box 12)
      8 x 11 Oil paint on paper
    - 1186-1121 Lillian (Box 12)
      5 7/8 x 4 Crayon on paper
    - 1187-1121 Vermont House (Box 12)
      11 5/8 x 9 1/8 Crayon on paper
    - 1188-1121 Vermont Meadow and Landscape (Box 12)
    - 1189-1121 Trace of Texture (Box 12)
      11 x 8 1/2 Graphite pencil and crayon on paper
    - 1190-1121 The Vermont Barn with Glebe Mountain (Box 12)
      9 1/2 x 6 Oil paint on paper
    - 1191-1121 Still Life (Box 12)
    - 1192-1121 Abstraction (Box 12)
      11 1/2 x 9 Watercolor and crayon on paper
    - 1193-1121 Sailing with the Beasts - A Sketch (Box 12)
      7 x 11 Pastels on paper
    - 1194-1121 [Self-Portrait] (Box 12)
    - 1195-1121 Good Shepard Figure from Sculpture (Box 12)
      4 1/8 x 5 1/8 Ink on paper
    - 1196-1121 Open-Mouthed Head (Box 12)
      6 x 4 Charcoal on paper
    - 1197-1121 New Year's Card (Box 12)
      4 x 6 Pastel and ink on paper
    - 1198-1121 Lillian and Children - Vermont (Box 12)
    - 1199-1121 Church Plans and Sections (Box 12)
      6 x 4 Ink on cardboard
    - 1200-1121 After J. Lipchitz His Sumerian Object (Box 12)
    - 1201-1121 Landscape (Box 12)
      3 3/4 x 5 Oil paint on paper
    - 1202-1121 Head (Box 12)
      9 1/8 x 12 Pastels on paper
    - 1203-1121 Baby (Box 12)
      4 x 5 1/4 Crayon on paper
    - 1204-1121 Male Figure (Box 12)
    - 1205-1121 [Boy and Dog] (Box 12)
      3 1/2 x 5 Ink on paper
    - 1206-1121 Drawings After Romanesque Capital Reliefs (Box 12)
    - 1207-1121 Figures (Box 12)
    - 1208-1121 Figures (Box 12)
    - 1209-1121 On Marble Wall on Lower Ground Floor Left (Box 12)
    - 1210-1121 [Howard] (Box 12)
    - 1211-1121 Allegorical Subject (Box 12)
    - 1212-1121 [Painter at Work] (Box 12)
      8 3/4 x 12 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1213-1121 Miriam and Ernest in Vermont (Box 12)
    - 1214-1121 Family in Vermont - Sketch (Box 12)
      5 x 8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1215-1121 Hill House (Box 12)
      6 1/4 x 7 3/4 Oil paint on paper
    - 1216-1121 Male Nude (Box 12)
    - 1217-1121 Lillian (Box 12)
      13 7/8 x 9 7/8 Oil paint on canvas board
    - Man Wrestling Bird (Box 12)
    - 3172-1121 Siena landscape (Box 13)
      Drawn on hotel brochure. 3 1/2 x 5 1/2 Ink on paper
    - 1219-1121 Miriam (Box 13)
    - 1220-1121 Lillian (Box 13)
    - 1221-1121 Lillian (Box 13)
    - 1222-1121 Icarus (Box 13)
      10 7/8 x 7 1/2 Pastels on paper
    - 1223-1121 Hill House with Curvilinear Vegetation (Box 13)
    - 1224-1121 Overlapping Shapes with Violin (Box 13)
      12 x 9 Crayon and watercolor on paper
    - 1225-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
      8 1/2 x 7 Pastels on paper
    - 1226-1121 Hill House, Garage, Barn - Vermont (Box 13)
      13 1/8 x 9 7/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1227-1121 A Brook in Vermont (Box 13)
      7 1/2 x 11 Oil paintl on paper
    - 1228-1121 Lillian with Hat (Box 13)
    - 1229-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
      8 1/2 x 6 Crayon on paper
    - 1230-1121 Lillian Reading - Vermont (Box 13)
    - 1231-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
    - 1232-1121 Hill House - Vermont (Box 13)
      9 x 6 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1233-1121 Lillian (Box 13)
    - 1234-1121 Untitled (Box 13)
      4 1/2 x 6 1/4 Oil paint on paper
    - 1235-1121 Jack in the Pulpit (Box 13)
    - 1236-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
    - 1237-1121 The Family in the Room at the Window (Box 13)
    - 1238-1121 Lillian (Box 13)
    - 1239-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
      10 5/8 x 7 Conte crayon on paper
    - 1240-1121 Lillian Reading (Box 13)
    - 1241-1121 Cubistic Head (Box 13)
    - 1242-1121 Lillian (Box 13)
    - 1243-1121 From Memory of Lipchitz (Box 13)
    - 1244-1121 Bombers and Anti-Aircraft Fire (Box 13)
    - 1245-1121 Bombers and Anti-Aircraft Fire (Box 13)
    - 1246-1121 Bombers and Anti-Aircraft Fire (Box 13)
    - 1247-1121 Bombers and Flag (Box 13)
    - 1248-1121 Bombers and Flag (Box 13)
    - 1249-1121 Bombers and Flag (Box 13)
    - 1250-1121 Paris (Box 13)
      2 7/8 x 4 3/8 Ink on lined paper
    - 1251-1121 Paris (Box 13)
      Inscribed on verso: Tuilleries. 2 7/8 x 4 3/8 Ink on lined paper
    - 1252-1121 Lillian Resting (Box 13)
    - 1253-1121 Italianate Perspective (Box 13)
      3 7/8 x 5 7/8 Ink on paper
    - 1254-1121 [Lillian] with Hat (Box 13)
    - 1255-1121 [Ernest] Playing Violin (Box 13)
    - 1256-1121 Lillian with Drying Hair (Box 13)
    - 1257-1121 Standing Pair (Box 13)
    - 1258-1121 Seated Person (Box 13)
    - 1259-1121 Young Woman (Box 13)
      6 x 4 Pastels and graphite pencil on paper
    - 1260-1121 Ernst (Box 13)
      Two sheets. 6 x 4 Crayon on paper
    - 1261-1121 Ernst (Box 13)
    - 1262-1121 Seated Woman (Box 13)
    - 1263-1121 Lillian (Box 13)
      Two sheets. 5 x 3 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1264-1121 Head and Flower (Box 13)
      Two sheets. 4 x 6 1/8 Ink on paper
    - 1265-1121 [After Grunewald] (Box 13)
    - 1266-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
    - 1267-1121 Sketch for Greeting Card (Box 13)
    - 1268-1121 Sketchbook of an Afternoon in Rawsonville (Box 13)
      Three sheets. 6 3/8 x 9 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 1269-1121 Crucifixion (Box 13)
    - 1270-1121 Mother and Child (Box 13)
    - 1271-1121 Crucifixion (Box 13)
    - 1272-1121 Desert Scene - Surrealist (Box 13)
    - 1273-1121 Three Persons on a Bed (Box 13)
    - 1274-1121 [Landscape] (Box 13)
      5 x 6 1/4 Ink on paper
    - 1275-1121 Head Looking Over Another Person's Shoulder (Box 13)
      5 1/4 x 8 1/4 Ink on paper
    - 1276-1121 Running Figure (Box 13)
    - 1277-1121 Ernst (Box 13)
      Two sheets. 5 7/8 x 4 7/8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1278-1121 Two Women (Box 13)
    - 1279-1121 Young Girl (Box 13)
    - 1280-1121 [Ernest] (Box 13)
    - 1281-1121 Bust (Box 13)
      6 1/4 x 4 3/8 Ink on paper
    - 1282-1121 Joe Milgram (Box 13)
    - 1283-1121 Griot = Alfred "Rosmer" and Marguerite (Box 13)
      Inscribed on recto: griot house in Perigny. 6 x 3 1/2 Ink on paper
    - 1284-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
    - 1285-1121 Young Woman (Box 13)
      scopecontentcard is invitation to a lecture by Georges Gaillard at New York University. 5 3/8 x 4 1/4 Ink on scopecontentcard
    - 1286-1121 [West 4th Street Backyard] (Box 13)
      3 x 4 15/16 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1287-1121 Lillian (Box 13)
    - 1288-1121 Ground Plan - Sketches (Box 13)
    - 1289-1121 Corner of Upstairs Bedroom - Vermont (Box 13)
    - 1290-1121 [Lillian] with Hat (Box 13)
      5 7/8 x 4 Graphite penil on paper
    - 1291-1121 Paris (Box 13)
    - 1292-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
    - 1293-1121 Vermont Meadow and Mountain (Box 13)
    - 1294-1121 [Vermont View] (Box 13)
    - 1295-1121 Young Girl (Box 13)
      11 x 7 3/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 1296-1121 Young Girl (Box 13)
      11 x 7 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 1297-1121 View from Hill House (Box 13)
      11 x 8 Pastels on paper
    - 1298-1121 Lillian (Box 13)
    - 1299-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
    - 1300-1121 [Miriam] (Box 13)
      7 x 10 1/2 Conte crayon on paper
    - 1301-1121 Cringing Figure #2 (Box 13)
    - 1302-1121 Cringing Figure #3 (Box 13)
      5 1/2 x 2 7/8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1303-1121 Cat (Box 13)
      5 7/8 x 3 7/8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1304-1121 Lillian (Box 13)
    - 1305-1121 Meyer's Slipper and Bell (Box 13)
      Drawing on verso. 6 1/4 x 9 5/8 Conte crayon on paper
    - 1306-1121 Vermont Scene Through Window (Box 13)
      8 1/4 x 9 1/2 Pastels on paper
    - 1307-1121 Head - Study (Box 13)
      13 1/4 x 9 1/2 Conte crayon on paper
    - 1308-1121 Girl with Flowers (Box 13)
    - 1309-1121 Lillian (Box 13)
      9 x 11 1/2 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1310-1121 Flowers (Box 13)
      7 x 10 1/8 Oil on cardboard
    - 1311-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
    - 1312-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
    - 1313-1121 Abstract Bust (Box 13)
      9 1/4 x 6 1/4 Gouache on paper
    - 1314-1121 Studies for Abstract Figure (Box 13)
    - 1315-1121 Study for Reclining Figures and Bust Figure (Box 13)
      9 x 12 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1316-1121 Bust Figure (Box 13)
      9 1/2 x 6 1/8 Gouache on paper
    - 1317-1121 Sketch for Painting of Abstract Bust (Box 13)
    - 1318-1121 Horse and Rider - [After Sculpture] (Box 13)
      Inscribed on verso: England? 4 x 6 Ink on paper
    - 1319-1121 Lillian (Box 13)
    - 1320-1121 Hill House Interior (Box 13)
      9 x 12 Gouache on paper
    - 1321-1121 Children Playing in Woods - Vermont (Box 13)
    - 1322-1121 Lillian and Children - Vermont Kitchen (Box 13)
    - 1323-1121 Miriam and Ernest and Linda Schapiro (Box 13)
    - 1324-1121 Door Message (Box 13)
      Inscribed on recto: We're up in the woods will be back around 3 or 3:30. 12 x 9 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1325-1121 Lillian - Vermont (Box 13)
      8 1/2 x 12 Oil paint on paper
    - 1326-1121 Lillian - Vermont (Box 13)
      9 1/2 x 13 1/8 Conte crayon on paper
    - 1327-1121 Ernest Picking Daisies (Box 13)
      9 x 11 5/8 Pastels on paper
    - 1328-1121 Young Child (Box 13)
    - 1329-1121 Unknown Girl (Box 13)
      12 x 9 1/2 Gouache and graphite pencil on paper
    - 1330-1121 Sketch for Painting of Family Picnic (Box 13)
    - 1331-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
    - 1332-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
    - 1333-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
    - 1334-1121 River Scene (Box 13)
    - 1335-1121 River Scene (Box 13)
      9 x 11 1/2 Pastels and gouache on paper
    - 1336-1121 Child or Doll (Box 13)
    - 1337-1121 Vermont Abstract #2 (Box 13)
    - 1338-1121 Vermont #1 (Box 13)
    - 1339-1121 Hill House (Box 13)
    - 1340-1121 Ernest (Box 13)
    - 1341-1121 Siren (Box 13)
      13 1/8 x 9 5/8 Conte crayon on paper
    - 1342-1121 Hill House Framed by House Window #1 (Box 13)
    - Vermont House (Box 13)
      Accompanied by detached diary page inscribed: Souvenir of Rawsonville, Vermont, July 1941. 5 7/8 x 4 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1344-1121 Vermont (Box 13)
    - 1345-1121 Ernest Gathering Flowers - Vermont (Box 13)
    - 1346-1121 Hill House (Box 13)
    - 1347-1121 Hill House (Box 13)
    - 1348-1121 Vermont House Views (Box 13)
    - 1349-1121 Vermont Views (Box 13)
    - 1350-1121 [Abstraction Machine] with Mirrored Form (Box 13)
    - 1351-1121 Female Nude (Box 13)
    - 1352-1121 Small Overlapping Shapes (Box 14)
      7 1/2 x 11 Pastels on paper
    - 1353-1121 Abstract #4 - Still Life with Fruit (Box 14)
    - 1354-1121 Abstract #5 - Still Life with Fruit (Box 14)
    - 1355-1121 Still Life with Fruit (Box 14)
      7 3/8 x 11 Watercolor on paper
    - 1356-1121 Overlapping Shapes (Box 14)
    - 1357-1121 Overlapping Perspective (Box 14)
    - 1358-1121 Abstraction - Still Life (Box 14)
    - 1359-1121 Abstraction #2 with Cone Shape (Box 14)
    - 1360-1121 Studio Interior (Box 14)
    - 1361-1121 Rawsonville House Kitchen (Box 14)
      7 1/2 x 11 Ink on paper
    - 1362-1121 Abstraction #3 with Cone Shape (Box 14)
    - 1363-1121 Still Life - Cup and Fruit (Box 14)
      9 1/2 x 12 Conte crayon on paper
    - 1364-1121 Coal Scuttle - Vermont (Box 14)
    - 1365-1121 Ovoids Over Blue and Green (Box 14)
      7 1/2 x 11 Gouache on paper
    - 1366-1121 Old Persian Monarch (Box 14)
    - 1367-1121 Purple Snake Over Inhabited Background Green, Red, Yellow (Box 14)
      7 3/8 x 11 Pastels on paper
    - 1368-1121 Field and Sky (Box 14)
      11 x 7 1/2 Pastels on paper
    - 1369-1121 Smaller Ovoids Over Blue and Green (Box 14)
      7 3/8 x 11 Gouache on paper
    - 1370-1121 Bottles (Box 14)
    - 1371-1121 Crab Apple Tree - Vermont (Box 14)
      11 x 7 5/8 Pastels on paper
    - 1372-1121 Black-Eyed Susans (Box 14)
      5 1/2 x 7 Oil paint on paper
    - 1373-1121 Landscape with Farmhouse and Barn (Box 14)
    - 1374-1121 Shapes on Vertical Bars (Box 14)
      11 x 7 1/2 Gouache on paper
    - 1375-1121 Lillian (Box 14)
    - 1376-1121 Miriamn (Box 14)
      11 x 7 1/2 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 1377-1121 Vermont House - North End (Box 14)
      7 1/2 x 11 Oil paint on paper
    - 1378-1121 Studio Interior - Sketch - Vermont (Box 14)
    - 1379-1121 Vermont Stream (Box 14)
      9 1/2 x 13 Oil paint on cardboard